A Guide to the Frank Norris Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6905
Frank Norris Collection 1898-1952
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6905
18 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1962 Nov 14
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Frank Norris to Paul Reynolds, 1898 Oct 22; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs Reynolds of his intention to sell the rights to his stories "
    From Dawn to Dark-Fighting
    " and "
    Surrender
    " to the Century Company. ]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, [1889] Jun 1; ALS, 1 p.
    [Replies to Richards' letter with mention of Norris' book
    Moran
    and
    McTeague
    chides him for inadvertently changing the title of
    thanks him for an invitation to London. ]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1899 Jun 13; ALS, 2 p.
    [Promises to send copy of
    Blix
    mentions completion of
    The Heroine
    , which will be published after serialization "somewhere"; says he is excited about material for a series of 3 novels based on the subject of American wheat; guesses that this project will take 3-4 years.]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1899 Oct 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Tells him that Samuel Sidney McClure is syndicating one of his stories which will be called
    A Man's Woman
    in the book publication (handled by Doubleday and McClure Co.); wonders if Richards would put this book on his list for publication in England; inquires about the success of
    in England, also about the royalties he might expect from their sales; requests critics' reviews of his book published.]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1899 Nov 27; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for 2 volumes that have not arrived yet; says he is curious if the book sells as well as the reviews indicate; speaks about an unpublished novel,
    Vandover and the Brute
    . ]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1899 Dec 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Says he is glad to know that
    is well received by English critics; wonders if Richards might consider taking over
    , which is in the hands of failing English branch of
    Harpers
    wonders about serialization of
    , and also of his last novel
    , in England, before publishing in book form; says a royalty of 10% is not satisfactory; asks for a better offer; requests the contracts for
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, [1900] May 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Gives him specific ideas for the printer regarding
    requests copies of the English edition of
    and and
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, [1900] Jun 29; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for copy of
    hopes that the publisher (Richards) will improve the cover design for
    , although he does not mean to interfere; hopes a secondary title will be omitted from
    says he was not pleased to see the subtitle "Love Idyll" under
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1900 Aug 28; ALS, 2 p.
    [Alludes to the fact that to date he has received only one statement for
    from Richards' firm; says he would like to know how the books
    have done; says he would, finally, love to see some money.]
  - Frank Norris to John O'Hara Cosgrave, 1900 Oct 31; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Discusses the possibility of an editor's position for him with Doubleday and Page but cannot promise anything; looks forward to his visit.]
  - Frank Norris to John O'Hara Cosgrave, 1900 Nov 5; Telegram
    [Complains that his statements and pecuniary settlements are now almost a year overdue; says his letters have been ignored; realizes that the English publication of his books has not been a financial success for the firm, but expects royalties just the same; threatens to find another publisher if the matter is not cleared up.]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1901 Mar 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Says he is willing to have
    A Woman's Man
    run in a London paper if he gets $100; announces the publication of
    The Octopus
    and brings up the possibility of an English publication.]
  - Frank Norris to Benjamin Orange Flower, 1902 Mar 18; ALS, 1 p.
    [Says he is encouraged and honored to see his work reviewed in the important magazine
    Arena
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, 1902 May 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of a letter and check for 48 pounds; mentions proofs of
    The Pit
    , and its serializing.]
  - John O'Hara Cosgrave to Elizabeth Sutton, 1902 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Verifies receipt of a manuscript.]
  - John O'Hara Cosgrave to Frank Norris, 1902 Oct 18; TLS, 3 p. (carbon) (w/ autograph corrections)
    [Proposes that he write an adventure novel in the style of
    Moran of the Lady Letty
    says it could be serialized in
    Everybody's
    and help the magazine along; expresses concern over Mrs. Norris' illness.]
  - Frank Norris to John O'Hara Cosgrave, n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Gives suggestions on how to alter a manuscript slightly, to make it a great story for
    urges Cosgrave to read the proofs of
    The Squid
    quickly, as the book has to be out by March 15.]
  - Frank Norris to Grant Richards, n. d.; ALS, 1 p. (fragment)
    [Discusses serializing, dramatizing and translation of an unknown work; requests a contract if all is agreeable.]